KIMBERLY (KIM) BELL

Greensboro, NC krbell4@gmail.com

336.782.1868

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kimbell4/

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER IN TEST (SDET)

Specializing in Cypress Test Automation

5+ years of experience in web development focusing on user experience.

2+ years of experience in automated testing and quality assurance.

Collaborative problem solver with experience assisting in the planning and execution to migrate from manual to automation testing. Identify and develop improvements to the automation framework, including CICD pipelines, NPM package, and internal documentation. Network with multiple teams to align on timelines, resolve issues, and work to decrease interruptions by improving communication and processes.

Toolbox: Cypress.io, Testing-Library, JavaScript, Typescript, ReactJS, Webpack, Git, Vim, Yaml, Bash, VSCode, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Github, qtest, BrowserStack, Styled-Components, HTML5, CSS3, Jira, Confluence

Skills: Automated Testing, Global Package (Internal) Management, TestOps, Gathering and Documenting Requirements, Agile Development, ADA Compliance, (software development life cycle) SDLC

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALLY BANK, Charlotte, NC

2018 to 2023

Senior SDET - Remote

2022 to 2023

Managed the priorities, coordination, and communication of work on the global internal NPM package. Subject Matter Expert (SME) for automation testing in the web space, focusing on Cypress.

- Adapted, updated, and improved global internal NPM package which reduced manual changes by individual teams and was used by 10 teams and multiple lines of business.
 - o Package was written in Javascript and Typescript and contained Cypress configurations
- Implemented the ability for teams to trigger automated tests manually or on scheduled CICD pipeline runs, reducing the hardening time for release cycles from hours to minutes in many cases.
- Developed and planned work around version migration strategies to keep packages and tools updated while not impacting teams as repositories using our tools went from 11 to 35 in 1 year.
- Standardized and documented tools, configurations, and common UI testing patterns so all teams and lines of business could align along common best practices and quality.
- Created Bash shell scripts to automate common changes and Javascript custom commands to increase efficiency writing tests.

Software Engineer

2018 to 2021

- Developed requested features in Ember and React as well as multiple ecosystems in order for new features to still be released while codebase was migrated to React.
- Trained team on Cypress in an effort to shorten lead time of adoption of automation testing.
- Assisted in planning, management, and execution of migrating automated tests from Ember to React in order to streamline and simplify the process as much as possible.

REASON CONSULTING CORPORATION (previously **TAX MANAGEMENT ASSOCIATES**)

Charlotte, NC 2015 to 2018

Software Engineer

2018 to 2018

- Provide the UI department with the necessary training, code snippets, and knowledge of technologies utilized within the department to increase efficiency from idea to product.
- Translate project requirements to user friendly applications using React.

Additional roles include Apprentice Developer and Junior Developer.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Javascript Application Development & Code Immersion Program (Ruby on Rails) Tech Talent & Strategy (previously Tech Talent South), Charlotte, NC

Master of Arts (MA), International Human Rights, University of Denver, Denver, CO **Bachelor of Arts (BA),** General Anthropology, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC